And, unfortunately, women have had less. And we are considered less. And so my attentions, where did they have to go? It was just ... you have to. And learn to stick up for yourself, hear your own voice. You hear the same words keep coming out all the time, and I got really lucky because I had an education. And I think if you can see it you can be it, you know? If you can see it, you can be it. You look at Pat, you look at other leaders, you look at these speakers, look at yourself, because everyone -- everyone -- can do something extraordinary. Every single person. PM: And your story, Billie, has inspired so many women everywhere. Now with the Billie Jean King Leadership Initiative, you're taking on an even bigger cause. Because one thing we hear a lot about is women taking their voice, working to find their way into leadership positions. But what you're talking about is even bigger than that. It's inclusive leadership. And this is a generation that has grown up thinking more inclusively -- BJK: Isn't it great? Look at the technology! It's amazing how it connects us all! It's about connection. It's simply amazing what's possible because of it. But the Billie Jean King Leadership Initiative is really about the workforce mostly, and trying to change it, so people can actually go to work and be their authentic selves. Because most of us have two jobs: One, to fit in -- I'll give you a perfect example. An African American woman gets up an hour earlier to go to work, straightens her hair in the bathroom, goes to the bathroom probably four, five, six times a day to keep straightening her hair, to keep making sure she fits in. So she's working two jobs. She's got this other job, whatever that may be, but she's also trying to fit in. Or this poor man who kept his diploma -- he went to University of Michigan, but he never would talk about his poverty as a youngster, ever -- just would not mention it. So he made sure they saw he was well-educated. And then you see a gay guy who has an NFL -- which means American football for all of you out there, it's a big deal, it's very macho -- and he talked about football all the time, because he was gay and he didn't want anybody to know. It just goes on and on. So my wish for everyone is to be able to be their authentic self 24/7, that would be the ultimate. And we catch ourselves -- I mean, I catch myself to this day. Even being gay I catch myself, you know, like, (Gasp) a little uncomfortable, a little surge in my gut, feeling not totally comfortable in my own skin. So, I think you have to ask yourself -- I want people to be themselves, whatever that is, just let it be. PM: And the first research the Leadership Initiative did showed that, that these examples you just used -- that many of us have the problem of being authentic. But what you've just looked at is this millennial generation, who have benefited from all these equal opportunities -- which may not be equal but exist everywhere -- BJK: First of all, I'm really lucky. Partnership with Teneo, a strategic company that's amazing. That's really the reason I'm able to do this. I've had two times in my life where I've actually had men really behind me with power. And that was in the old days with Philip Morris with Virginia Slims, and this is the second time in my entire life. And then Deloitte. The one thing I wanted was data -- facts. So Deloitte sent out a survey, and over 4,000 people now have answered, and we're continuing in the workplace. And what do the millennials feel? Well, they feel a lot, but what they're so fantastic about is -- you know, our generation was like, "Oh, we're going to get representation." So if you walk into a room, you see everybody represented. That's not good enough anymore, which is so good! So the millennials are fantastic; they want connection, engagement. They just want you to tell us what you're feeling, what you're thinking, and get into the solution. They're problem-solvers, and of course, you've got the information at your fingertips, compared to when I was growing up. PM: What did the research show you about millennials? Are they going to make a difference? Are they going to create a world where there is really an inclusive work force? BJK: Well, in 2025, 75 percent of the global workforce is going to be millennials. I think they are going to help solve problems. I think they have the wherewithal to do it. I know they care a lot. They have big ideas and they can make big things happen. I want to stay in the now with the young people, I don't want to get behind. (Laughter) PM: I don't think there's any chance! But what you found out in the research about millennials is not really the experience that a lot of people have with millennials. BJK: No, well, if we want to talk -- OK, I've been doing my little mini-survey. I've been talking to the Boomers, who are their bosses, and I go, "What do you think about the millennials?" And I'm pretty excited, like it's good, and they get this face -- (Laughter) "Oh, you mean the 'Me' generation?" I say, "Do you really think so? Because I do think they care about the environment and all these things." And they go, "Oh, Billie, they cannot focus." (Laughter) They actually have proven that the average focus for an 18-year-old is 37 seconds. (Laughter) They can't focus. And they don't really care. I just heard a story the other night: a woman owns a gallery and she has these workers. She gets a text from one of the workers, like an intern, she's just starting -- she goes, "Oh, by the way, I'm going to be late because I'm at the hairdresser's." (Laughter) So she arrives, and this boss says, "What's going on?" And she says, "Oh, I was late, sorry, how's it going?" She says, "Well, guess what? I'd like you leave, you're finished." She goes, "OK." (Laughter) No problem! PM: Now Billie, that story -- I know, but that's what scares the boomers -- I'm just telling you -- so I think it's good for us to share. (Laughter) No, it is good for us to share, because we're our authentic selves and what we're really feeling, so we've got to take it both ways, you know? But I have great faith because -- if you've been in sports like I have -- every generation gets better. It's a fact. With the Women's Sports Foundation being the advocates for Title IX still, because we're trying to keep protecting the law, because it's in a tenuous position always, so we really are concerned, and we do a lot of research. That's very important to us. And I want to hear from people. But we really have to protect what Title IX stands for worldwide. And you heard President Carter talk about how Title IX is protected. And do you know that every single lawsuit that girls, at least in sports, have gone up against -- whatever institutions -- has won? Title IX is there to protect us. And it is amazing. But we still have to get the hearts and minds -- the hearts and minds to match the legislation is huge. PM: So what gets you up every morning? What keeps you sustaining your work, sustaining the fight for equality, extending it, always exploring new areas, trying to find new ways ... ? BJK: Well, I always drove my parents crazy because I was always the curious one. I'm highly motivated. My younger brother was a Major League Baseball player. My poor parents did not care if we were any good. (Laughter) And we drove them crazy because we pushed, we pushed because we wanted to be the best. And I think it's because of what I'm hearing today in TED talks. I think to listen to these different women, to listen to different people, to listen to President Carter -- 90 years old, by the way, and he we was throwing these figures out that I would never -- I'd have to go, "Excuse me, wait a minute, I need to get a list out of these figures." He was rattling off -- I mean, that's amazing, I'm sorry. PM: He's an amazing man. (Applause) BJK: And then you're going to have President Mary Robinson, who's a former president -- Thank you, Irish! 62 percent! LGBTQ! Yes! (Applause) Congress is voting in June on same-sex marriage, so these are things that for some people are very hard to hear. But always remember, every one of us is an individual, a human being with a beating heart, who cares and wants to live their authentic life. OK? You don't have to agree with somebody, but everyone has the opportunity. I think we all have an obligation to continue to keep moving the needle forward, always. And these people have been so inspiring. Everyone matters. And every one of you is an influencer. You out there listening, out there in the world, plus the people here -- every single person's an influencer. Never, ever forget that. OK? So don't ever give up on yourself. PM: Billie, you have been an inspiration for us. BJK: Thanks, Pat! (Applause) Thanks, TED! Thanks a lot!
Y, por desgracia, las mujeres han tenido menos. Y se nos considera menos. Y así mi atención, ¿a dónde debía ir? Era solo... simplemente tienes que hacerlo. Y aprender a encararte a ti misma, oír tu propia voz. Oyes las mismas palabras todo el tiempo, y tengo mucha suerte porque tengo una educación. Y creo que si puedes verlo puedes llegar a serlo, si puedes verlo, puedes lograrlo. Si ves a Pat, ves otros líderes, ves a esos ídolos, te ves ti misma, porque todo el mundo, cada uno de nosotros, puede hacer algo extraordinario. Cada persona. MP: Y tu historia, Billie, ha inspirado a muchas mujeres en todas partes. Ahora, con la Iniciativa de Liderazgo Billie Jean King, estás actuando por una causa aún mayor. Porque algo que escuchamos mucho es que las mujeres están levantando su voz, trabajando para encontrar su camino en las posiciones de liderazgo. Pero de lo que hablas es aún más grande que eso. Es un liderazgo integrador. Esta es una generación que ha crecido pensando de modo más inclusivo BJK: ¿No es genial? ¡Mira la tecnología! Es increíble cómo nos conecta a todos. Se trata de la conexión. Es simplemente increíble lo que hace posible. Pero la Iniciativa de Liderazgo King Billie Jean es mucho de la fuerza de trabajo, de cómo tratar de cambiarla, que la gente puede ir a trabajar y ser sus auténticos yos. Dado que la mayoría de nosotros tenemos dos trabajos: Uno, para adaptarse... Te daré un ejemplo perfecto. Una mujer afroamericana se levanta una hora antes de ir a trabajar, se arregla el pelo en el baño, va al baño, probablemente, cuatro, cinco, seis veces al día para arreglarse pelo, para asegurarse de que encaja. Así, ella tiene 2 empleos. Ella tiene este otro trabajo, sea lo que sea, pero también tratar de encajar. O este pobre hombre que logró su diploma, --fue a la Universidad de Michigan, pero nunca habló de su pobreza de joven, nunca-- simplemente no lo mencionó. Se aseguró de que vieran que era bien educado. Y luego ves a un chico gay que está en la NFL --lo que significa el fútbol americano para todos Uds. algo grande, muy machista-- y hablaba sobre fútbol todo el tiempo, porque era gay y no quería que nadie lo supiera. Y así a así. Así que mi deseo para todos es puedan ser su auténtico yo 24/7, eso sería lo máximo. Y nos sorprendemos, quiero decir, me sorprendo yo misma. Incluso siendo gay me sorprendo a mí misma (¡huy!) estando algo incómoda en mis entrañas, sintiéndome no totalmente cómoda en mi propia piel. Por eso, creo que hay que preguntarse, quiero que la gente sea ella misma, lo que sea, pero que lo sea. MP: La primera investigación de la Iniciativa de Liderazgo mostró que que en estos ejemplos que acabas de usar, muchos tenemos el problema de ser auténticos. Pero lo que se ve en esta generación del milenio, que se han beneficiado de toda esta igualdad de oportunidades, quizá no iguales, pero existen en todo lugar. BJK: Primero, soy muy afortunada. Estar asociada con Teneo, una empresa estratégica que es increíble, es realmente la razón para poder hacer esto. Dos veces en mi vida realmente he tenido hombres con poder apoyándome. En los viejos tiempos con Philip Morris con Virginia Slims, y esta es la segunda vez en toda mi vida. Y ahora Deloitte. Lo único que quería eran datos, hechos. Así Deloitte envió una encuesta, y más de 4000 personas la han respondido, y seguimos en el lugar de trabajo. ¿Y qué sienten los milenio? Sienten mucho, pero lo que es tan fantástico es... nuestra generación pensaba: "Obtendremos representación". Así que si vas a una sala, ves a todos representados. Ya no es lo suficientemente bueno, aunque sea bueno. La generación milenio es fantástica; quiere conexión, compromiso. Solo quieren que nos digan lo que sientes y piensas, y encontrar una solución. Pueden resolver problemas, y por supuesto, se tiene la información al alcance, en comparación a cuando yo era pequeña. PM: ¿Qué mostró la investigación sobre esta generación? ¿Van a marcar una diferencia? ¿Crearán un mundo en que haya realmente una fuerza de trabajo inclusiva? BJK: Bueno, en 2025, el 75 % de la fuerza laboral mundial será de la generación milenio. Creo que ayudarán a resolver problemas. Creo que tienen los medios para hacerlo. Sé que les importa mucho. Tienen grandes ideas y pueden hacer que se logren grandes cosas. Quiero quedarme en el ahora con los jóvenes, no quiero estar detrás. (Risas) PM: ¡No creo que haya oportunidad! Pero lo que descubriste sobre la generación milenio no es realmente la experiencia que mucha gente tiene con la generación del milenio. BJK: No, bueno, si queremos hablar... OK, he hecho mi pequeña mini-encuesta. He estado hablando con los Boomers, que son sus jefes, y me voy, "¿Qué piensa Ud. acerca de los milenio?". Y estoy bastante emocionada, como si fuera bueno, y ponen esta cara (Risas) "Oh, la generación 'yo'?". Yo digo: "¿De verdad lo crees? Porque yo creo que se preocupan por el medio ambiente y todas estas cosas". Y siguen, "Oh, Billie, no pueden concentrarse". (Risas) Ellos realmente han demostrado que el enfoque promedio de un joven de 18 años es de 37 segundos. (Risas) No pueden concentrarse. Y no les importa. Acabo de escuchar una historia la otra noche: una mujer es dueña de una galería y tiene estos trabajadores. Recibe un texto de una de las trabajadoras, como una interna, que acaba de comenzar: "Oh, por cierto, voy a llegar tarde porque estoy en la peluquería". (Risas) Así que ella llega, y este jefe dice, "¿Que tal todo?". Y dice: "Oh, es tarde, lo siento, ¿cómo va todo?". Ella dice: "Bueno, ¿adivina qué? Te vas, estas despedida". Ella dice: "Bien". (Risas) ¡No hay problema! PM: Billie, esa historia... Lo sé, eso es lo que asusta a los del "baby boom". Digo, que creo que es bueno compartir. (Risas) De verdad es bueno compartir, porque somos nuestro auténtico yo y lo que sentimos, así que tenemos que tomar las dos cosas. Pero tengo gran fe, porque... si has estado en deporte como yo, cada generación es mejor. Es un hecho. Con la Fundación Deportiva de Mujeres en defensa del Título IX todavía, intentamos mantener la protección de la ley, porque está en una posición débil siempre, así que realmente preocupa, y hacemos mucha investigación. Es muy importante para nosotros. Y lo quiero oír de la gente. Pero realmente tenemos que proteger el Título IX que representa a todos. Y oyeron al Presidente Carter hablar de cómo el Título IX está protegido. Y sabes que cada demanda que las niñas, al menos en el deporte, han ido en contra --cualesquiera que sean las instituciones-- ¿ha ganado? Título IX está ahí para protegernos. Y es increíble. Pero todavía hay que ganar los corazones y las mentes, que corazones y mentes coincidan con la legislación es grande. PM: ¿Qué te hace levantar todas las mañanas? ¿Qué te mantiene motivada en tu trabajo, sostener la lucha por la igualdad, extendiéndola, explorando nuevas áreas, encontrando nuevas maneras...? BJK: Siempre volvía locos a mis padres porque siempre era muy curiosa. Estoy muy motivada. Mi hermano menor era jugador de las Grandes Ligas. A mis pobres padres no les importaba si éramos buenos. (Risas) Y los volvimos locos porque insistíamos, presionábamos por querer ser los mejores. Y creo que es por lo que estoy hoy en las charlas de TED. Creo que al escuchar a estas mujeres diferentes, escuchar a diferentes personas, escuchar al presidente Carter de 90 años, por cierto, y esas cifras que mostró que yo nunca... Me tengo que ir, "Disculpe, espere un minuto, necesito una lista de estas cifras". Es la caña, quiero decir, eso es increíble, lo siento. MP: Es un hombre increíble. (Aplausos) BJK: Y tendrán a la presidenta Mary Robinson, quien es expresidenta. ¡Gracias, irlandeses! ¡62 %! ¡LGBTI! ¡Sí! (Aplausos) El congreso votará en junio el matrimonio entre personas del mismo sexo, son cosas que para algunas personas es muy difícil de escuchar. Pero recuerden, cada uno de nosotros es un individuo, un ser humano con un corazón que late, que se preocupa y quiere vivir su vida auténtica. No tienen que estar de acuerdo con nadie, pero todos deben tener oportunidad. Creo que todos tenemos una obligación de seguir avanzando la aguja, siempre. Y esta gente ha sido muy inspiradora. Todo el mundo importa. Y cada uno es un factor de influencia. Ud. que nos escucha en el mundo, además de la gente de aquí, cada persona es un factor de influencia. Nunca, nunca lo olviden. ¿De acuerdo? Así que no vuelvan a renunciar a Uds. mismos. PM: Billie, una gran inspiración para nosotros. BJK: Gracias, Pat. (Aplausos) ¡Gracias, TED! ¡Muchas gracias!